Guide to the Pittsburgh Cultural Trust Records, 1975-2021 CTC.2000.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pittsburgh Cultural Trust Records
1975-2021
1983-2000
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Pittsburgh Cultural Trust
CTC.2000.02
112 Linear Feet (338 document boxes and 96 architectural designs)
The Pittsburgh Cultural Trust was formed in 1984 with the goal of re-establishing an arts and entertainment district downtown. The Benedum Center, Fulton Theater, Harris Theater, and the Wood Street Galleries are all owned and operated by the Cultural Trust. This collection contains the records of the Cultural Trust from 1984 through 1999. Included are marketing materials, financial records, institutional and real estate development, and the production records of the Benedum Center.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Pittsburgh Cultural Trust in 2000. Additional materials were donated in 2022.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into nine series:
I. Benedum Center, 1983-1998
II. District Development, 1979-2000
III. Art Services, 1989-1997
IV. Harris Theatre / Art Cinema Renovation, 1989-1995
V. Institutional Development, 1986-1998
VI. Executive Offices, 1983-1999
VII. Finance, 1984-1996
VIII. Marketing, 1975-1999
IX. Audio Visual Materials, 2020-2021
History
In the early 1970s a group of prominent Pittsburghers led by H.J. Heinz II began an effort to return the Penn and Liberty corridor of downtown to the thriving theater district it once was. This area had been in steady decline since the 1950s. The era of the Nixon, Stanley, Alvin and Pitt theatres had long since passed. They all were demolished, dormant, or in disrepair. The Howard Heinz Endowment funded the renovation of the Loew's Penn Theater in 1967. In 1971, the new Heinz Hall was unveiled as the new home of the Pittsburgh Symphony Society. In 1984, this group officially created the Pittsburgh Cultural Trust with the goal of creating a cultural district in downtown Pittsburgh. Their current mission statement is "to stimulate the economic and cultural development of Pittsburgh through the development and promotion of a downtown arts and entertainment district. The Trust encourages and presents diverse performing and visual arts programs in the Cultural District." The Trust purchased the Stanley Theatre and completely renovated it. It was renamed the Benedum Center for the Performing Arts and was dedicated in 1987. After the $43 million project was completed, the Cultural Trust began to develop other properties in and around Penn and Liberty avenues.
Jack Heinz named Carol Brown as the Trust's first president in 1986. She served until her retirement in 2001 when Kevin McMahon, former executive vice president of the John F. Kennedy Center, was named as the new president.
The Trust offers assistance and provides services to Pittsburgh local arts community. It organizes free quarterly gallery crawls through the Cultural District, internship opportunities, and student and teacher workshops. Other businesses and organizations located in the Cultural District have joined the Cultural Trust in the revitalization project of the Penn-Liberty Historic District. The Trust has facade restoration grants available to buildings that are within the Cultural District to help improve the overall appearance of the district. The Trust and the city of Pittsburgh have spent millions of dollars on beautification and improvements in the Cultural District.
Due to the theatre renovations, art installations, and other improvements all led to the creation of the Cultural District that was designated a national historic district in 1987. The newest addition to the Cultural District is the O'Reilly Theater and was completed in 1999. The 650 seat theater was designed by Michael Graves and is the home of the Pittsburgh Public Theater.
Previous Citation
Pittsburgh Cultural Trust Records, 1926-2000, CTC.2000.02, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Related Material
Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Theatre Programs, 1840-present, CTC.1966.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Archives & Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Scope and Content Notes
The records of the Pittsburgh Cultural Trust contain the organization's office files from the beginning, in 1984, to the opening of the O'Reilly Theater in 1999. The majority of the materials concern the restoration of the Stanley Theatre and its reopening as the Benedum Center for the Performing Arts, the settlement files for every show that performed at the Benedum Center from its opening in 1987 to 1998, the development of the Cultural District between Penn and Liberty avenue, the planning and construction of the O'Reilly Theater, and finally the advertising and marketing information for a majority of the productions presented by the Cultural Trust as well as the marketing of the Trust itself.
The vast majority of the collection consists of paper files, but there are a few other types of materials, including photographs, slides, ledgers, newspaper clippings, and architectural designs. There are very few materials that date before the early 1980s.
City planning -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Arts -- Economic aspects -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Art and society -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies, etc.; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Social life and customs; Art and popular culture -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Theater; Cultural District (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Community foundations -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Benedum Center for the Performing Arts (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Pittsburgh Cultural Trust
- Benedum Center for the Performing Arts, 1983-1998; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The Benedum Center of the Performing Arts is the primary venue of the Cultural Trust. Most of the Trust's major presentation programs are performed at the Benedum Center. The information in this series relates to the operational files for the venue and settlement files for all the productions that performed at the theater.
  - Benedum Center records, 1983-1999; 1.
    This subseries contains the administrative and operational files of the Benedum Center of the Arts. Included are files concerning the restoration and reopening of the theatre and correspondence with partner arts organizations such as the Civic Light Opera, the Pittsburgh Ballet, and the Pittsburgh Opera.
    - Acoustic panels, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Administrative reports, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
    - Advance box office payments, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Americans with Disabilities Act, 1991-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Americans with Disabilities Act requirements, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Arts advocacy, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Arts in Focus, Ltd. Binocular rental, 1993-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bookings, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Constituents booking policies, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Constituents non-booking and scheduling policies, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Capital budget update, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Chandelier restoration photos (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Civic Light Opera, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
    - Civic Light Opera, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
    - Civic Light Opera choice seats, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Civic Light Opera interest in advance sales, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Civic Light Opera lease agreements, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Civic Light Opera Pittsburgh Symphony correspondence, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Complaints, 1987-1997 (Box 3, Folder 3-5)
    - Compliments, 1988-1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Computer systems, 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Computer usage fees, 1988-1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Constituents newspaper clippings, 1989-1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Contractor's contracts, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Co-presenters (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Curtain's Up! Festival weekend, September 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Damages to patrons, 1987-1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Dorothy Parker t-shirt, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Downtown police patrol, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Duquesne Light, 1992-1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Electronic draft capture online authorization, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Engineering correspondence, 1987-1999 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Executive survey, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Fabri-Coate, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Facilities information, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Financial needs analysis, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Fire system, 1987-1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Furnishings, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Gift certificates, 1987-1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Gift shop, 1987-1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - House and stage information (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - HVAC system, 1987-1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Interior and exterior sketches (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Interiors, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Inner lobby, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Internships, 1987-1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Jerit Boys maintenance study, November 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Job descriptions, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Joint management of Pittsburgh Broadway Series, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - Joint management of Pittsburgh Broadway Series, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Joint subcommittees of Pittsburgh Symphony Society and Pittsburgh Trust for Cultural Resources boards, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Joint subcommittees of Pittsburgh Symphony Society and Pittsburgh Trust for Cultural Resources staff, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lease, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Lighting board replacement, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lobby chandelier photos (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Marketing, 1987-1991 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
    - Master schedules, 1991-1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - McCune report newspaper clippings, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Memorandum on management structure by Economic Research Assoc., 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Moving picture machine operators correspondence, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Navarro correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
    - Navarro correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
    - Navarro correspondence, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Navarro correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Negative air pressure, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1983-1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 5-7)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Opening gala, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Opening gala newspaper clippings, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Opening gala program and press packet, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Opening gala promotional materials, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Opera rental rates changeover costs, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Operations study by University of Pittsburgh students, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Outreach task force, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - OSHA, February 1993 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Other theatre renovations and openings, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Performers photographs (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Personnel, 1985-1999 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Personnel, 1987-1994 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Personnel study, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Photocopier information, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre, 1986-1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre, 1996-1998 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Pittsburgh Dance Council, 1989-1991 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Pittsburgh Dance Council, 1996-1999 (Box 12, Folder 8-10)
    - Pittsburgh Opera, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Pittsburgh Opera, 1996-1999 (Box 12, Folder 12-14)
    - Pittsburgh Public Theater newspaper clippings, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Pittsburgh Symphony, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Procedures for changing the marquee, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Promotional materials for the Benedum Center, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Rental rates schedule, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Residents and constituents booking policies and procedures, 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Residents and constituents meetings, 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Scheduling, 1989-1993 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
    - Scheduling Civic Light Opera (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Scheduling Pittsburgh Ballet, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Scheduling Pittsburgh Dance Council, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Scheduling procedures, 1981-1994 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Scrapbook of Benedum opening season, 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Seating (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Smoking lounge, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Seventh floor reservations, 1995-1998 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Shaver report, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Sign reconstruction, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Sound equipment, 1987-1991 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Staff meetings, 1987-1997 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Stanley theatre history (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Stanley theatre memories, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Stanley theatre opening (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Stanley theatre photographs (photocopies) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Stanley theatre renovation, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Surrounding area information, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Syria Mosque, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Telecheck, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Telemarketing, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Tenth anniversary proclamation, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Theater utilization data (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Theatre Historical Society of America, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - UDAG, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - WQED fundraiser donation, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - WQED marquee donation, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - WQED trade, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - WQED pledges, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Benedum Center performances - settlement files, 1987-1998; 2.
    This subseries contains a settlement file for every show that played at the Benedum Theater from October 1987 through December 1998. The materials are arranged chronologically by the opening date of the production. Most of the shows were presented by local theatre orgnaizations such as the Pittsburgh Broadway Series, the Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre, the Pittsburgh Dance Council, Pittsburgh Opera, and the Civic Light Opera. Each file folder title lists the production name and, if non-local, the presenter. Occasionally productions that were a part of the Pittsburgh Broadway Series were performed at the Heinz Hall for the Performing Arts, these productions are included and noted as such. Also included are files for shows that were planned, but for some reason or another were cancelled.
    - Luciano Pavarotti, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Turandot, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Renaissance Productions / Pyramid Productions - Winans and the Clark Sisters, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Great Gatsby, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Repertory Works, October 1987 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Cavalleria rusticana and I Pagliacci, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Cats, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Hansel & Gretel, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Nutcracker, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Nikolais Dance Theatre, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Swan Lake, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Press conference, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Macbeth, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 3-5)
    - Dance Theatre of Harlem, March 1988 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Don Giovanni, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Michael Feinstein, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Etudes, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Variations, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Carmen, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - American Pop'ra Company - Nimrod and the Tower of Babel and Senator Joe, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Canadian Brass, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Jazz Tap Ensemble, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Next Big Thing Productions - Natalie Cole (cancelled), May 1988 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Civic Light Opera pre-production week, June 1988 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Michelob Class Acts - Gladys Knight & the Pips, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Together Again, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Wizard of Oz, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 13-14)
    - Funny Girl, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Annie Get Your Gun, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Sound of Music, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Mystery of Edwin Drood, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - WTAE and Tecate Imported Beer - Linda Ronstadt, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Aida, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Four Temperaments Eau de Vie, 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - la boheme, 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Ebony fashion show, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Inspiration 88, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Salome, 1988-1989 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Kid Brother, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Don Quixote, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Brighton Beach and Biloxi Blues, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - WTAE-TV - Broadway Bound, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Born Yesterday, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Spirit of Pittsburgh, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - WTAE-TV - Rosemary Clooney's White Christmas Party, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - WTAE-TV - Mitzi Gaynor, 1988-1989 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Nutcracker, 1988-1989 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - les Miserables, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Anything Goes, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - WTAE-TV - Boys Choir of Harlem, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Concerto Barocco and Sunset and Music, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Great Gatsby, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Martha Graham Dance Company, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - H.J.D. Enterprises - Roots of Rock and Roll Volume XIV, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Creamer Dickson Basford - McDonald's World's Largest Concert, 1989-1990 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - WTAE-TV - the Clancy Brothers, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - WTAE-TV - Kathleen Battle, 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Laura Dean Dancers, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Tales of Hoffmann, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - the River, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Mayoral debate, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - WTAE-TV - the Flying Karamazov Brothers, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Alvin Ailey American Dance Theatre, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - the Merry Widow, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Tosca featuring Pavarotti, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Fifth Anniversary Maecenas Benefit, 1989-1990 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Werther (cancelled), 1988 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Frankfurt Ballet, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - T.P.B. Entertainment - Dells Stylistics and Delphonics (cancelled), 1989 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Record Breakers International - Paula Abdul and the Loose Ends, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - the Odd Couple, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Annie, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Grease, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - My Fair Lady, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - a Chorus Line, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Electric Factory Concerts - Shenna Easton, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - the Unsinkable Molly Brown, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - the King and I, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - the Supreme Grand Inspectors General of the Thirty-Third and Last Degree of the Ancient Accepted Scottish Northern Masonic Jurisdiction of the U.S. of A. convention, 1988-1989 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - International Poetry Forum - Nana Mouskouri, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Pittsburgh International Folk Theatre World Showcase, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Hispanic Forum of Western Pennsylvania - Sotavento, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - PACE Theatrical Group - Gypsy, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
    - Driving Miss Daisy, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Steve Lawrence and Eydie Gorme, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Raymonda Variations and a Midsummer Night's Dream, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Heinz Hall - Fiddler on the Roof, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Elektra, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Sotavento, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Allegro Brillante and the Prodigal Son and Western Symphony, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Starlight Express, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Starlight Express, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    - the Alexandrov Red Army Song and Dance Ensemble, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Top Rank INC and Joe Hand Promotions - Leonard / Duran III Boxing Closed Circuit TV, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Michelob Class Acts - Patti La Belle and James Ingram, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - the Boys Choir of Harlem, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - American Theater Arts for Youth Inc. - Babes in Toyland, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - the Nutcracker, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - les Miserables, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 1-4)
    - Mama I Want to Sing, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Pilobolus Dance Theatre, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
    - Pittsburgh Filmmakers - Henry V film, 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Jennifer Muller / THE WORKS, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Giselle, 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Theme & Variations and Music and Return to the Strange Land, 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Heinz Hall - Chess, 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - la Traviata, 1989-1990 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Mefistofele, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Garden Club of Allegheny County Symposium (cancelled), 1989 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Heinz Hall - Cats, 1989-1990 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Mendelssohn: Violin Concerto and In the Glow of the Night and Gaite Parisienne, 1989-1990 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Lyon Opera Ballet Cendrillon, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Bob Newhart, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Jose Carreras in concert (cancelled), 1990 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - American Theatre Arts for Youth Inc. - Wizard of Oz, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Lar Lubovitch, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Silky Soul Tour - Maze featuring Frankie Beverly, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Michael Matthews - Mamma, Don't, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Three Rivers Arts Festival - Three Rivers Film Festival, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Heinz Hall - Shirley MacLaine Out There Tonight, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Oklahoma, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Cinderella, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - 42nd Street, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Sweeny Todd, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Student Prince, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - West Side Story, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 10-11)
    - Royal Ballet, 1989-1990 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Home Box Office - Criminal Justice movie premiere, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Sankai Juku, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Performing Arts for Children - A Children's Presentation, 1989-1990 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Swan Lake, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Heinz Hall - the Music of Andrew Lloyd Webber, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Othello, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - the Flying Dutchman, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Between Ourselves and Con Amore Western Symphony, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Belkin Productions - Harry Connick Jr., 1990 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Africa Oye!, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - M. Butterfly, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - A.H. Enterprises - the Whispers, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - American Theater Arts for Youth Inc. - Babes in Toyland, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Nutcracker, 1990 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Sarafina!, 1990-1991 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Paul Taylor, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - WYJZ-AM - the Late Great Ladies of Blues and Jazz, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Grand Hotel, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Mummenschanz, 1990-1991 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Trisha Brown Company, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 5)